Guide to the Consumer Reports. Esther Peterson papers, 1953-1997 and undated RL.11791
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- IOCU/UN (International Organization of Consumers Unions/United Nations), 1964-1993 and undated; 3
  - General Files, 1964-1993 and undated; 4
    - Meetings--Regional Conference, Santiago, Chile, 1990 Nov. 19-23 (Box 9)
    - Mission Report by Michael Van Hulten regarding New York trip, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Montevideo conference, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Nairobi conference, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Nairobi conference--Clippings (Box 19)
    - Nairobi conference--Notebooks, 1988; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - National Conference on USA/UN, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Next Thirty Years by Michael Van Hulten, 1989 Oct. 12 (Box 9)
    - NGO Committee on Development--Steering Committee, 1983 (Box 9)
    - NGO CONGO (Conference of Non-Governmental Organizations), 1984 (Box 9)
    - NGO Council of Washington Representatives to the UN, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
    - NGO involvement, 1982-1985 (Box 9)
    - NGO lists, 1990 (Box 9)
    - NGOs, 1982-1985; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Notes, 1984-1989 (Box 9)
    - Op-Ed: Consumer guidelines, approximately 1984 (Box 9)
    - P.I.C. (Prior Informed Consent), 1989 (Box 9)
    - Paper--Roefie Hueting, "The Fallacy of the Growth of Consumption", approximately 1990 (Box 9)
    - Papers--Code, 1980-1987 (Box 9)
    - Peterson pre-appointment, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Pharmaceutical exports, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
    - Pill-fering the Poor: Drugs and the Third World, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Poland package, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Proposed UN consumer guidelines compared to consumer protection laws in the United States, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Reagan Administration criticism essays, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Reports, 1983-1991 (Box 9)
      Reports on UNA/USA, IOCU reports to the UN, a statement on the International Year of Peace and the Consumer
    - ROENA (Regional Office for Europe and North America), 1990 (Box 9)
    - S.I.S. (Selective Information Service) materials, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Sao Paolo correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 19)
    - Saurwein, Virginia, approximately 1986 (Box 9)
    - Second Committee statements, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Sim, Foo Gaik, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Society for International Development (S.I.D.), 1991 (Box 9)
    - Speech in Sao Paolo, Brazil--3 Encontro Rhodia de valorização de consumidor (in Portuguese), 1988 (Box 9)
    - Statements on the UN consumer protection guidelines, 1984-1993 (Box 9)
      Includes statements and some clippings from LexisNexis.
    - Statements on the UN consumer protection guidelines, 1984-1993; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Streisand Foundation, 1988-1989 (Box 9)
    - Talking points--Guidelines, undated (Box 9)
    - The Case against "The Case Against the UN guidelines for Consumer Protection", 1988 (Box 9)
    - Tobacco/Smoking, 1989; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - UN and consumer guidelines, 1984-1992; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - UN Bill of Rights, 1989 (Box 9)
    - UN common goals, 1989 (Box 9)
    - UN Decade for Women: Forward-Looking Strategies, 1985 (Box 9)
    - UN International Business Council, 1982-1987 (Box 9)
    - UN pending issues and contacts, 1985 (Box 9)
      Contains a few letters and notes on Bhopal.
    - UN Representatives correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
    - UNA (United Nations Association) Conference, 1989 (Box 9)
    - UNA/USA NY (United Nations Association of the United States of America), 1985-1991; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - UNDP (United Nations Development Programme), 1989 (Box 9)
    - UNEP (UN Environment Program), 1989 (Box 9)
    - UNESCO (United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization), 1990 (Box 19)
    - UNICEF (United Nations Children's Fund), 1987-1989 (Box 9)
    - UNIFEM (United Nations Development Fund for Women), 1988 (Box 9)
    - US clippings, 1984 (Box 9)
    - USA/UN National Conference, Washington, D.C., Nov. 9-11, 1989 (Box 19)
    - Verbatim records of UN meetings, 1984-1985 (Box 9)
    - WHO (World Health Organization)--77th Executive Board Meeting, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Women and children reports and resolutions, 1985-1987 (Box 10)
      Includes reports from the UN Commission on the Status of Women
    - Women in Development, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Working documents--Pan American Health Organization, 1989; 3 folders (Box 10)
      Collection of working documents of the 34th Meeting of the Directing Council of the Pan American Health Organization, the 41st Meeting of the Regional Committee of the World Health Organization
    - World Consumer Rights Day, 1989-1992; 2 folders (Box 10)
      Press kits and promotional material for World Consumer Rights Days.
    - World Consumer Rights Day--Correspondence, 1993 (Box 10)
    - World Development Forum, 1990 (Box 10)
  - CTC (United Nations Commission on Transnational Corporations), 1975-1993; 5
    - 1990 Code Developments (Box 11)
    - 1991 Code Developments (Box 11)
    - 1991 UN Code consultations (Box 11)
    - 19th Session of the Commission on Transnational Corporations, 1993 Apr. (Box 11)
    - Article: Asante, Samuel: Good Corporate Citizens in International Business, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Article: Caplan, Richard: Tracking Transnationals, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Article: CFA News, 1990 Apr.-May (Box 11)
    - Article: Code of Conduct--International Barometer, 1990 Jan.-Feb. (Box 11)
    - Article: Congressional Record, Code of Conduct, 1990 Mar. 29 (Box 11)
    - Article: CTC Reporter, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Article: IOCU Newsletter Call to Action, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Article: UN Interdependent, Code of Conduct, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Binder (Luncheon with Hill Staffers?), 1992 (Box 11)
    - Bush Administration: Letters of Support for the Code of Conduct, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Catalyst for Recent Developments, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Center for Transnational Corporations, 1986-1990 (Box 11)
    - Clippings, 1987; 2 folders (Box 11)
      Assorted clippings from national news outlets on multinationals and the Code of Conduct for Transnational Corporations. Contains clippings from a Japanese newspaper featuring Japanese consumer activist Katsuko Nomura. Folder 2 also contains a statement from the International Chamber of Commerce and minutes from a meeting of the UN International Business Council.
    - Clippings--US Foreign Investment, 1988; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Code Debate: UN New York, 1990 Oct. 18 (Box 11)
    - Code Material for Hill, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Code Material--Extras, 1983-1986 (Box 11)
    - Code Notes, approximately 1988; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Code of Conduct, 1991 Apr. 22-26 (Box 11)
    - Code of Conduct Discussion Paper, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Code of Conduct Economic Committee Report, 1992 July (Box 11)
    - Code of Conduct: Binder 1, approximately 1990; 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Code of Conduct: Binder 2, approximately 1990; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Code Push: Group of 77 mailing list, 1990 May 7 (Box 11)
    - Code Push: Incoming/outgoing correspondence, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Code Resolutions, 1977-1978 (Box 11)
    - Code Symposium--Washington, DC, 1990 Oct. 25 (Box 11)
    - Code Updates and Summaries, 1991 (Box 11)
    - Code--History, 1975-1987; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Code--Mandatory/Voluntary Issue, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Code--Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 11)
    - Collins, Jennifer--Financial assistance, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Congressional Hearings, 1984-1990 (Box 11)
    - Congressional Research Service: Code/Kissinger, 1990 (Box 12)
    - Consultants: Asher, Allan, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Consultants: Collins-Foley, Jennifer, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Consumer Protection guidelines, 1969-1986 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1992; 7 folders (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: Applebaum, Judith, 1992 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: Bolton, John, 1989-1990 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: Bradlow, Danny, 1987-1988 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: Code of Conduct, 1989-1991; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: Wood, Asher, 1992 (Box 12)
    - Criteria for Sustainable Development Management, 1990 (Box 12)
    - Detailed Examination of Outstanding Issues, 1989 (Box 12)
    - Dissent--Business Perspective, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Dissent--International Chamber of Commerce, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Dissent--Miscellaneous Letters, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Dissent--State Dep't., 1990-1991 (Box 12)
    - Dissent--UK Letter, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC)--Sustainable Development, 1991 (Box 12)
    - ECOSOC: Completion of the Code of Conduct, 1986 (Box 12)
    - ECOSOC: Outstanding Issues, 1985 (Box 12)
    - ECOSOC: Recent Developments, 1986 (Box 12)
    - ECOSOC: Solutions to Outstanding Issues, 1985 (Box 12)
    - ECOSOC: TNCs, 1989; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Empretec (in Spanish), 1989 (Box 12)
    - Environmental concerns, 1989 (Box 12)
    - Environment--Criteria for Sustainable Development Management, 1990 (Box 12)
    - Esther Peterson--Foreign Agent, 1984 (Box 19)
    - Ethics statements, 1989-1990 (Box 12)
    - Food processing industry in developing countries, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Foreign direct investment, 1992-1993; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Goa Research Institute, 1990-1991 (Box 19)
    - Government Investment Standards and the Consumer Interest, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Guidelines for Consumer Protection--House hearings, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Guiton, Bonnie, 1989-1990 (Box 12)
    - Hansen, Peter, 1984-1989 (Box 12)
    - Hearings: House, 1989 Nov. 15; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Hearings: Senate, 1984; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Hearings: Senate--Code of Conduct, 1990 Oct. 11; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Hearings: Senate--Environment, Sept. 21 (Box 13)
    - Heritage Foundation--TNCs Injure Poor Nations, 1987 (Box 13)
    - High-level roundtable, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Hill correspondence, undated (Box 13)
    - Hill lobbying material, undated (Box 13)
    - Historical perspective, 1988 (Box 13)
      Includes a few clippings in multiple languages (French, German, Dutch, Danish, and Japanese).
    - Hong Kong Conference, 1991 (Box 13)
    - International Chamber of Commerce, 1987 (Box 13)
    - International Cooperative Alliance, 1986 (Box 13)
    - International development, 1989 (Box 13)
    - International Workshop on Negotiating Joint Venture Agreements, 1990 (Box 13)
    - IOCU--Brochure art work, 1990 (Box 13)
    - IOCU--Brochure: Code of Conduct, 1990 (Box 13)
    - IOCU--Brochure: Code of Conduct--correspondence, 1990 (Box 13)
    - IOCU--Esther Peterson's notes, approximately 1991 (Box 13)
    - IOCU--Financial assistance to groups, 1992 (Box 13)
    - IOCU--Information kit on the UN Code of Conduct on transnational corporations, 1991; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - IOCU--Position paper on UN Code of Conduct, 1986 (Box 13)
    - IOCU--Statements and articles by Esther Peterson, 1989-1991 (Box 13)
    - IOCU--Support budget, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Kennedy/Vargo, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Keyes, Alan, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - Lobbying--Ambassador's packet, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Lobbying--Dunlap strategy memo, 1992 (Box 13)
    - Lobbying--House of Representatives, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Lobbying--Luncheon, 1992 Feb. (Box 13)
    - Lobbying--Mailing lists (IOCU), undated; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Lobbying--Notes for hearings on Code, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Lobbying--Press releases, clippings, 1991; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Lobbying--Senate, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Lobbying--UN Delegate's list, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Meeting--Code Conference Re--Ruth H. Carew, Los Angeles, 1990 Nov. 3 (Box 13)
    - Meeting--IOCU Mini-Conference, the Hague, 1990 May 1-8 (Box 13)
    - Meeting--Malaysia Conference, 1989-1990 (Box 13)
    - Meeting--UN CTC Code session, New York, NY, 1990 Apr. 4-5 (Box 13)
    - Meeting--US Department of State, Washington, D.C., 1990 Apr. 27 (Box 13)
    - Meeting reports, 1989-1993 (Box 13)
      Includes meeting reports for the 1992 and 1993 sessions of the Commission on Transnational Corporations
    - NCBA (National Cooperative Business Association), 1990 (Box 13)
    - New York Code meeting, 1991 Sept. 23-27 (Box 13)
    - NGO statements Re: Code, approximately 1990 (Box 13)
    - Op-Ed: Code, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Op-Ed: Code, 1988 (Box 19)
    - Panel discussion of the Code of Conduct, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Proposed consumer positions, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Publicity, 1983-1988 (Box 13)
    - Report on the 18th Session (Allan Asher_, 1992 (Box 13)
    - Roundtable on foreign direct investment in China, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Rubin, Seymour, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Schneider, Claudine, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Secretary Schultz letter, approximately 1986 (Box 13)
    - Sen. Mathias memo, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Senate/House Hearings, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Senate/House Hearings Kit, 1989-1990 (Box 13)
    - South Africa, 1977-1985 (Box 13)
    - Special Session on Transnational Corporations, 1985 June 6-21 (Box 13)
    - State Department, 1985-1986 (Box 14)
    - Statement by IOCU regarding Code, 1986-1987; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Statement of expert advisers, 1985 (Box 14)
    - Statements on Code, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Statements pro-Code, approximately 1987 (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: 1990 Draft with memo--Miguel Marin Bosch (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: Consultation, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: Issue--Banking, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: Issue--Corrupt Practices, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: Issue--Environment, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: Issue--Foreign Direct Investment, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: Outstanding issues, 1990-1991 (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: Progress reports, approximately 1992 (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: Resolution to start over, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Status of Code: TNC documents, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Summary Points: Code of Conduct, approximately 1989 (Box 14)
    - Support--Labor groups, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Support--Other groups/people, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Synopsis of Outstanding Issues, 1987-1988 (Box 14)
    - TAG (Transnational Action Group), 1987 (Box 19)
    - Testimony, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Testimony--CTC--Sustainable Development, 1989 Apr. 7 (Box 14)
    - Testimony--House, Code of Conduct, 1989 Nov. 15 (Box 14)
    - The New Code Environment, by John Kline, 1989 (Box 14)
    - TNCs and the Environment, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Transnational Corporations, South Africa, and Namibia, 1985 (Box 14)
    - UN Code of Conduct Fact Sheet, 1987-1988 (Box 14)
    - UN Code of Conduct Nears Completion, 1988 (Box 14)
    - UN Code of Conduct on TNCs--What Has Been Achieved So Far, approximately 1986-1987 (Box 14)
    - UN publications and press releases, 1984-1989; 4 folders (Box 14)
    - UN reports, 1991 (Box 14)
    - UN reports, 1984-1988 (Box 14)
    - UN shakeup, 1992 (Box 14)
    - UNCTC Current Studies, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Visit by Michael van Hulten, 1990 Jan. 6-7 (Box 14)
    - White papers and clippings, 1986 (Box 14)
      Includes papers on the Code of Conduct, as well as statements by Peterson and Samuel K. Asante.
    - Why Support the UN Code of Conduct on Transnationals?, approximately 1986 (Box 14)
    - Why the Code, approximately 1986 (Box 14)
    - Why Wait? Building a Framework for Service Transactions, 1987 (Box 14)
    - Working Book on Code (Resurrected) and guidelines, 1992 (Box 14)
      Compiled materials on the Code in the 1990s and the Consumer Protection Guidelines
    - Working paper, 1985-1986 (Box 14)
    - Yatron Subcommittee, 1987 (Box 14)
- CIIG/PIA (Consumer Insurance Interest Group/Professional Insurance Agents), 1976-1993 and undated; 4
  The CIIG/PIA series, along with the Aetna and Health/Insurance series, document Peterson's advocacy work on health care and insurance in the 1980s, and reveal her personal investment in matters of elder care and aging. Because she was working on multiple projects at once, there is some overlap in correspondence, particularly across IOCU/UN and CTC files, and across the different health insurance projects.
  - ACCI E.P. Consumer Policy Forum, 1990 (Box 14)
  - Accomplishments, 1993 (Box 14)
  - American Council on Consumer Interests (ACCI), 1987-1991 (Box 14)
  - American Mustang Newsletter, 1988 (Box 14)
    American Council for Independent Life Underwriters
  - Americans for Economic Renewal, Inc., 1989 (Box 14)
  - An Urban Expressway Survival Guide, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Articles for approval, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Articles on PIA/CIIG partnership, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Ashoka, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Austin, TX: Office of Consumer Protection, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Auto insurance, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Auto insurance clippings, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Auto Insurance Rates in the U.S. (white paper), 1988-89; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Awards program, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Background: CIIG/PIA, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Bell, Fletcher, Insurance Commissioner, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Board Member--CIIG--Current file, 1991-1992 (Box 15)
  - Breach of Trust: The Failure of the Insurance Commissioner to Protect California Consumers, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Building layout, approximately 1988 (Box 15)
  - Bush Administration clippings, 1988-1991 (Box 15)
  - Center for National Independence in Politics (CNIP), 1990 (Box 15)
  - CIIG Fact Sheet, undated (Box 15)
  - Citizen Ambassador program, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Citizen's Transition Project, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Clippings, 1988-89; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Clippings--Insurance, 1979-1988 (Box 19)
  - Colorado Convention, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Commissioner tenure correspondence, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Consumer advocate bill, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Consumer Interest Research Institute, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Consumer Watch columns, 1991-1993 (Box 15)
  - Consumer's Guide to Insurance for High School Students, 1981 (Box 15)
  - Contract, undated (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1991; 5 folders (Box 15)
  - Correspondence--Claybrook, Joan, 1990-1992 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence--Forbes, Paul, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence--State insurance, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Council on Economic Priorities (CEP), 1989-1990 (Box 15)
  - CPCU book, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Dinner party, 1990 Dec. 7 (Box 15)
  - DYG health care survey, 1991 (Box 15)
  - DYG health care survey, 1991; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Expense records, 1987-1988 (Box 15)
  - Factors Contributing to Auto Insurance Claim Costs, 1989 (Box 15)
  - Forbes--PIA material, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Future agendas/direction, 1991 (Box 15)
  - General information and documents, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Governor's Commission on Insurance, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Griffith Foundation, 1989 May 3 (Box 15)
  - Happy birthday cards to Esther, undated (Box 19)
  - Health insurance, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Indiana Convention, 1989 May 9 (Box 15)
  - Insurance and aging, 1987 (Box 15)
  - Insurance Consumer Action Panel (ICAP), 1976 (Box 15)
  - Insurance Consumer Affairs Exchange Conference, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Insurance Consumer Bill of Rights and Responsibilities, 1989 (Box 15)
  - Insurance Department survey, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Insurance Legislators National Conference, 1989 (Box 15)
  - Insurance speech and interview material, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Insurance speech and interview material, 1990 (Box 19)
  - Insureline columns, undated (Box 15)
  - International Medical Services for Health (InMed), 1991-1992 (Box 15)
  - Itineraries, 1987-1988 (Box 15)
  - Las Vegas Convention, 1989; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Letter of Agreement, 1987 (Box 15)
  - Maryland insurance, 1989 (Box 15)
  - Match-making Elderly with Young, 1988 (Box 15)
    Material on child care in late 1980's
  - Meeting agendas and minutes, 1987-1992 (Box 15)
  - Meeting materials, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Meeting notes, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Meetings: AIA, NCLI, ACLI, 1989-1992 (Box 15)
  - Memphis Insurance Day, 1989 (Box 15)
  - Minneapolis Convention (9/12/1990) (Box 15)
  - Model Insurance Standards, 1988-1989 (Box 15)
  - Model Regulation Service, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Model Standards news conference, 1989 (Box 16)
  - NAIC (National Association of Insurance Commissioners), 1988 (Box 16)
  - NAII (National Association of Independent Insurers), 1989 (Box 16)
  - NAII clippings, 1989 (Box 16)
  - NAPSLO (National Association of Professional Surplus Lines Offices) Annual Convention, 1989 (Box 16)
    NAPSLO merged with the American Association of Managing General Agents (AAMGA) in 2017 to form the Wholesale & Specialty Insurance Association (WSIA)
  - NAPSLO: "Tort Reform--the Road to Predictability", 1989 (Box 16)
  - News and Updates, 1992-1993 (Box 16)
  - News releases, 1988-1990 (Box 16)
  - No-Fault Solution, undated (Box 16)
  - NY Insurance Alliance Convention, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Omaha, Nebraska, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Pharmaceutical Dialogue Group, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Pharmaceutical Manufacturer's Association (PMA), 1985-1987 (Box 16)
  - PIA--Background information, 1986-1989 (Box 16)
  - PIA--Congressional Research Service information pack, 1987 (Box 16)
  - PIA--National Consumer Forum, 1987 (Box 16)
  - PIA--National Convention, 1987 (Box 16)
  - PIA--National Convention, 1990 (Box 16)
  - PIA--Newspaper articles, 1986; 3 folders (Box 16)
    Includes newspaper articles and other clippings on the liability insurance crisis and tort reform. Includes a few reports and white papers, including an ICAP Annual Report and the White House Report of the Tort Policy Working Group.
  - PIA--Staff directory, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Report to PIA Board of Directors, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Robert Saffer--Ketchum Communications, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Society of Consumer Affairs Professionals in Business (SOCAP), 1991 (Box 16)
  - Solvency Roundtable, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Solvency Roundtable--Correspondence, 1991 (Box 16)
  - State Insurance clippings, 1988 (Box 16)
  - State Insurance Commissioner's Study, 1988-1990 (Box 16)
  - State Insurance Department evaluations, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - State Insurance Department operations correspondence, 1989 (Box 16)
  - State Insurance Department study, 1990 (Box 16)
  - State Insurance Departments--Clippings, publications, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Status Reports, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Study of State Insurance Department Operations, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Study of State Insurance Department Operations Press Kit, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Subcommittee meeting memos, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Survey of Consumer Services of State Insurance Department Operations, 1990-1991 (Box 16)
  - Tort reform, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Virginia annual national convention, 1990 (Box 16)
- Aetna, 1987-1988 and undated; 5
  - Choice Time correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - Choice Time program, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Choice Time television spot and drafts, 1988-1989 (Box 16)
  - Choice Time Thinking Ahead on Long Term Care, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Contacts, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Contracts, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Final meeting notes, undated (Box 16)
  - Hospice, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Insurance information, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Ketchum Public Relations media clips, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Long term health care, 1987-1988 (Box 16)
  - Medicare, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Mission Oaks: Choice Time, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Publications, 1988 (Box 16)
  - S.O.S. "Save Our Security", 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Seminar curriculum, 1987 (Box 16)
- Health/Insurance, 1980-1993 and undated; 6
  - AARP (American Association of Retired Persons)--Health, elderly, 1985-1993 (Box 16)
  - AARP--History, 1983-1990 (Box 16)
  - AARP--National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC), 1988-1991 (Box 16)
  - AARP--National Steering Committee, 1987-199 (Box 17)
  - AARP--Steering Committee meeting, 1990 Oct. 8 (Box 17)
  - Aging, 1980-1982 (Box 17)
  - National Committee for Quality Assurance, 1987 (Box 17)
  - Peterson speech on long-term care and insurance, 1987 (Box 17)
  - USHC (United Seniors Health Cooperative)--Background, 1991-1993 (Box 17)
  - USHC--Correspondence and press releases, 1989 (Box 17)
  - USHC--Current, 1991-1992 (Box 17)
  - USHC--Updates, 1986-1989 (Box 17)
- Print Materials, 1978-1993 and undated; 7
  - Action Line (Corning Ware), 1978 (Box 17)
  - African Women's Assembly: Women and Sustainable Development, 1989 (Box 17)